David Alexander Orejuela Caicedo

ELECTRONIC ENGINEER I SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



Address

Santiago de Cali - Colombia

Phone Number +57 3194974259

Email Address daorejuela1@outlook.com

> Linkedin daorejuela1

Github daorejuela1

HOBBIES

Dancing

Movies

Hiking

LANGUAGES

English B2

Spanish Native

SKILLS

Python3

Advanced

Bash

Intermediate

C Advanced

Ruby On

Rails Intermediate

ABOUT

Electronic Engineer & Software developer with 3 years of professional experience being in rolls of research and development. Capable of creating stunning MVP's in record time. Looking to contribute with python-ruby backend skillset to a company impacting humankind for the better.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mercadolibre

Software development analyst

(October 2021 - Present)

- Offered easy to use machine learning tools, so that data can be securely used and transformed by applying Python, Jupyter, Bash, Java & Flask.
- In partnership with 15 coworkers defined clean code strategies to reduce the need for hotfixes.
- Developed documentation for client issues & requirements to avoid repeating bugs.

Koombea

Junior Back-End Developer

(May 2021 - September 2021)

- Conceptualized and developed server-side solutions by using the Ruby On Rails framework and best quality practices according to the client needs.
- · Assisted in the troubleshooting, maintainance & documentation of APIs for a long-term project.
- Collaborated with team of six to fulfill the client requirements on web, android & iOS platform.

Real Group Interactive

(October 2018 - January 2020)

Development Engineer

- Improved LiDAR, GPS, IMU storage & user experience by using python, QT & VTK automating the data capture process.
- Delivered the code for 4 new LiDAR products used by multiple clients in 1 year.
- Conceptualized and drafted new technologies to increase LiDAR data performance for different client needs.

EDUCATION

Holberton School

(January 2020 - Present)

Full Stack Software Engineer

- Fundamentals of front-end and back-end development (Git, JavaScript, Python, C, HTML),
- Currently doing a specialization on the Linux Kernel capabilities by reproducing C standard library functions, command-line tools, blockchain, advanced data structures and algorithms.

University of San Buenaventura Bachelor's Degree Electronic Engineering

(December 2012 - February 2017)

4.7

 Key knowledge of network communication, parallel programming, specialized in embedded programming with ASIC and FPGA solutions using VHDL, C and MatLab.

PROJECTS

Warehouse Management System

https://github.com/daorejuela1/our-warehouse

Software as a services App developed on Ruby On Rails with the MVC pattern, uses Stripe to handle subscriptions from companies, allows the clients to upload items and mark whenever someone is using then, HTML, CSS & Bootstrap on the front-end.

Custom Shell

https://github.com/daorejuela1/shell_v2

Linux advance command interpreter written in C, that executes commands that are read from the standard input by using System Calls, handles redirections and pipelines.

Serpent Algorithm

https://github.com/daorejuela1/serpent

Computer Science MatLab implementation of the second finalist of the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) contest.